ROBERT SWALLOW

La Quinta, CA 92253

Phone: 714 388 4846 | Email: robertiswallow@gmail.com

 $Linked In: \underline{https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-swallow-252319a8/} \quad | \ \ GitHub: \underline{https://github.com/rjswallow} \ | \ \ GitHub: \underline{https:/$

Portfolio: https://rjswallow.github.io/React Portfolio/#/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with an experienced background in corporate sales and marketing. Certified in Full Stack Web Development through the University of Washington's Coding Bootcamp. Excellent at bringing the best elements of a development team together for clear and effective execution of project timelines. Exceptionally comfortable engaging with markets, identifying consumer pain points and proposing scalable solutions. Known to share a positive attitude, have strong communication, and a stoic work ethic weather part of a team or leading one.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Browser Based Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Handlebars,

Local Storage, React.js

Database Technologies: MongoDB, MySQL

Server Side Technologies: MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), Session Storage, User

Authentication

Deployment Technologies: Heroku, Git

PROJECTS

FridGenerator: https://github.com/b-hexsoul/fridGenerator | https://brandon.is-a.dev/fridGenerator/

FridGenerator is a user friendly application which recommends food and drink recipes based on the ingredients users input from their fridge.

- Worked with a small team to design and modify a visually appealing and innovative front-end layout.
- Part of the team responsible for analysing and debugging new code.
- Worked with team to test the UI and functionality of the application.
- Maintained clear communication between front-end design and back-end development team to continually create best user experience.

GarageExchange: https://github.com/samrod777/GarageExchange | https://frozen-earth-11241.herokuapp.com/

GarageExchange is a client/server application which enables users to post and exchange belongings rather than dispose of them.

- Worked with a tight-knit team to design and modify a creative and user friendly front end layout.
- Part of the team responsible for analysing and debugging new code.
- Tested the performance and functionality of the application.

PandaPatter: https://github.com/Jessica264365/PandaPatter | https://pandapatter.herokuapp.com/

Panda Patter is a responsive React application built off the Google translate API with added components allowing users to create flashcards to review for language learning.

- Acted as project manager for the team, fostered clear communication, and enforced Git standards
- Contributed to creating ideation, setting up database, and logic of flashcard functionality.
- Maintained functionality by testing user experience and modifying UI for optimal performance.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Bootstrap, Node, Express, MongoDB(and Mongo Atlas), Mongoose, React, Google API, Axios, and FireBase(and Firestore), Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Sales Development Rep

Invoca (Tech/Marketing Software) -

Sept 2018 - May 2020

Prospected Enterprise level companies and contacted C-Suite level executives in a specific territory to schedule "opportunities" for a team of Regional Sales Directors.

- Consistently part of a team that achieved awards and recognition for exceeding KPI's and metrics.
- Exceeded daily sales goals while developing sales engagement techniques and strategies
- Created ongoing live docs with successful phone scripts and objective handles and used them to mentor, coach, and role play with junior associates.

Sales Associate

BigSpeak Speakers Bureau -

June 2016 to Sept 2018

Owned sales cycle from start to finish - Negotiated contracts between Speakers and the hiring organization.

- Successfully achieved monthly/quarterly quotas while maintaining strong performance in outbound and inbound roles.
- Utilized proven sales and persuasion principles to progress delicate sales cycles.
- Ensured smooth contract execution with clear communication and management between the Speakers and customers.

Outbound BDR

BigSpeak Speakers Bureau -

June 2016 to Sept 2018

Responsible for driving all outbound business development strategy.

- Increased monthly outbound activity by 200%
- Created monthly target customer groups while continuously updating and maintaining customer management database.
- Prospected companies and organizations across the US to find events for keynote speakers.
- Managed to successfully exceed role metrics while also managing the high volume inbound specialist role.

Inbound Specialist

BigSpeak Speakers Bureau -

June 2016 to Sept 2018

Responsible for qualifying and distributing all inbound sales leads.

- Created a lead distribution system to ensure quick lead response times and accurate information gathering.
- Simultaneously managed all inbound lead channels for the company, including inbound calls, emails, and
 live chats.
- Was exceptionally detail oriented and used custom questioning strategies to acquire as much information about the client as possible to provide for the sales team.

Design Consultant: Sales

Restoration Hardware -

Nov 2015 - June 2016

Responsible for engaging with customers on showcase floors, creating customer profiles, and passing those design opportunities to the design team.

- Established successful customer engagement strategies which enabled success in creating new customer profiles
- Would qualify and pass customer profiles to the design team, creating large revenue opportunities for in-home design services.

Assistant Manager - Sales

Lucky Brand -

Sept 2012 - Nov 2015

Responsible for every aspect of the day to day supervision of sales, staff, and stock.

- District Champion: E-Commerce
- Top Seller E-Com: Top 2% E-Commerce Transactions: West Coast Region
- Top Seller Retail: Top 10% volume in district YTD
- Top Seller Omni: Closes 20% more Omni-Sales than district average
- Top 100 Associates List: Best Rank 58th

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington Full Stack Web Program:

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor's Degree: Religious Studies - UCSB, Santa Barbara, CA